<!--Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2006, v.4002-->
<!DOCTYPE learningContent PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Learning Content//EN" "../../dtd/learningContent.dtd"[]>
<learningContent id="GUID-7952A6DF-6D75-495D-A213-A63F400F38AE" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The DITA learning and training content specialization</title>
  <shortdesc>This topic introduces the technical specifications for DITA learning
and training content</shortdesc>
  <learningContentbody>
    <lcIntro>
      <p>The DITA for learning technical specifications provide a starting
point for those professionals looking to take advantage of DITA and apply
it to learning. The specifications were drawn up by a sub-committee of the
OASIS DITA Technical Committee, composed of DITA experts and learning professionals,
all with a keen interest in creating a specialization that addresses the unique
needs of the learning community. These specifications are not meant to be
the end point, but rather the launching pad and the foundation from which
DITA extends itself into the world of learning and training.</p>
    </lcIntro>
  </learningContentbody>
  <concept id="_2">
    <title>Introducing the DITA for Learning Spec</title>
    <conbody>
      <section>
        <title>The topic types</title>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Learning plan</dt>
            <dd>The learning plan allows a learning design team to provide descriptive
data about the learning need being addressed and the mechanics of how it will
be addressed. It provides a way for learning professionals to chart a clear
path for a learning endeavor prior to authoring any actual content. The data
provided in this topic type will provide entire learning teams, including
design and development personnel the path and tools that will most likely
be required to fulfill the obligations of the learning need.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Learning overview</dt>
            <dd>The learning overview identifies the learning objectives, includes other
information helpful to the learner, such as prerequisites, duration, intended
audience, and can include information and strategies that seek to gain attention
and stimulate recall of prior learning. A learning overview provides a bird's
eye view of the content and let a potential learner know what to expect as
they proceed through the rest of the content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Learning summary</dt>
            <dd>The learning summary recaps and provides context for the learning objectives,
provides guidance to reinforce learning and long-term memory, and may pose
questions to enhance encoding and verification of the learning content. The
learning summary brings closure for the learner on the content and summarizes
the key learning points covered in the main body of the content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Learning content</dt>
            <dd>The learning content provides the learning content itself, and enables
direct use of content from DITA task, concept, and reference topics, as well
as additional content of any topic type that supports the specific objectives
declared in the learning overview topic type. It is here that a learner can
expect to find the actual "content" that supports the objectives identified
by the overview.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Learning assessment interactions</dt>
            <dd>The learning assessment presents instruments that measure progress, encourage
retrieval, and stimulate reinforcement of the learning content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>The Interactions Domain</title>
        <p>Although Interactions
were built to support the notion of assessment they have been created as a
DITA domain, and made available in the lcInteractions element in learningAssessmentbody.</p>
        <p>Because
the interactions are defined as a DITA domain, however, they can be made available
for use in other topic types, if that is desirable. For example, you could
make lcInteractions available for use in learning activities within the body
of a learning content topic.</p>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>The learning map domain</title>
        <p>The learning map domain defines the following set of specialized topicref
elements:<dl><dlentry><dt>learningGroup</dt><dd>A container to introduce and group learning objects into higher-level
organizations, such as course-level, module-level, or lesson-level. A learningGroup
can contain other learningGroup elements, allowing you to organize learning
content at course, module, or other higher-levels of hierarchy.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningObject</dt><dd>A container to introduce and group the topic references for a learning
object. </dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningPlanRef</dt><dd>A topic reference to a learning plan topic.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningOverviewRef</dt><dd>A topic reference to a learning overview topic, which introduces the learning
object.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningContentRef</dt><dd>One or more topic references to a learning content topic, or a topic,
task, concept, reference or other specialized topic.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningSummaryRef</dt><dd>A topic reference to a learning summary topic.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningPreAssessmentRef</dt><dd>A topic reference to a learning assessment topic that is used as a pre-assessment.</dd></dlentry><dlentry><dt>learningPostAssessmentRef</dt><dd>A topic reference to a learning assessment topic that is used as a post-assessment.</dd></dlentry></dl></p>
        <p>A DITA learning object in a map domain looks like the following:</p>
        <pre>
&lt;learningObject collection-type="sequence" href="../ImportModules/top_Overview.dita" type="learningOverview"&gt;
  &lt;learningPlanRef href="../ImportModules/learningPlan_topic.dita" type="learningPlan"/&gt;
  &lt;learningOverviewRef href="../ImportModules/lo_Overview.dita" type="learningOverview"/&gt;
  &lt;learningContentRef href="../ImportModules/lo_Content.dita" type="learningContent"/&gt;
  &lt;learningPostAssessmentRef href="../ImportModules/lo_Assess.dita" type="learningAssessment/"&gt;
  &lt;learningSummaryRef href="../ImportModules/lo_Summary.dita" type="learningSummary"/&gt;
&lt;learningObject&gt;
</pre>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Learning metadata</title>
        <p>In addition to standard DITA
metadata, learning-specific metadata is also available for use with learning
topics and learning maps, through a DITA domain specialization. This learning
metadata follows the IEEE LOM standard for learning objects metadata. </p>
        <ul>
          <li>lcLom, makes the lom elements available in the learning topics</li>
          <li>lomAggregationLevel </li>
          <li>lomContext </li>
          <li>lomCoverage </li>
          <li>lomDifficulty </li>
          <li>lomInstallationRemarks </li>
          <li>lomIntendedUserRole </li>
          <li>lomInteractivityLevel </li>
          <li>lomInteractivityType </li>
          <li>lomLearningResourceType </li>
          <li>lomOtherPlatformRequirements </li>
          <li>lomSemanticDensity </li>
          <li>lomStructure </li>
          <li>lomTechRequirement </li>
          <li>lomTypicalAgeRange </li>
          <li>lomTypicalLearningTime</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </conbody>
  </concept>
</learningContent>
<?Pub Caret?>
<?Pub *0000005034?>